<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Matrix42 Self-Service</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:56:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/cropped-r1-s-p-a-eurome-516-logo-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Matrix42 Self-Service</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Trump’s secret weapon consolidating the GOP: Fear</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/trumps-secret-weapon-consolidating-the-gop-fear/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/trumps-secret-weapon-consolidating-the-gop-fear/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=29</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some anti-Trump voters say the social cost of speaking out can be too high to take the risk. It&#8217;s the same fear other Republicans have noted in elected officials. By Alex Tabet IOWA CITY, Iowa — Anti-Donald Trump Republicans know they are in the middle of a critical moment to stop the former president’s political comeback. ... <a title="Trump’s secret weapon consolidating the GOP: Fear" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/trumps-secret-weapon-consolidating-the-gop-fear/" aria-label="More on Trump’s secret weapon consolidating the GOP: Fear">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some anti-Trump voters say the social cost of speaking out can be too high to take the risk. It&#8217;s the same fear other Republicans have noted in elected officials.</p>
<p>By Alex Tabet</p>
<p>IOWA CITY, Iowa — Anti-Donald Trump Republicans know they are in the middle of a critical moment to stop the former president’s political comeback. But for some, the steep cost of voicing resistance to Trump often renders them silent.</p>
<p>“If you go against Trump, like — you’re over,” said Kyle Clare, 20, a member of the University of Iowa’s College Republicans.</p>
<p>“I don’t talk about Donald Trump a lot because I’m afraid of the backlash,” said Jody Sears, 66, a registered Republican from Grimes, Iowa.</p>
<p>“If you would say something negative about Trump, we had one person that would just go bang for your throat,” said Barbra Spencer, 83, a former Trump voter describing her experience living in senior apartments in Spillville, Iowa.</p>
<p>Trump still enjoys broad popularity in the Republican Party, and that’s driving his polling leads among Republicans in Iowa, New Hampshire and every other state ahead of the 2024 primaries. But he has also used that popularity to enforce unity. And the same impulse that has led Republican officeholders to avoid criticizing Trump because of potential threats to their safety and their jobs is also holding back rank-and-file voters from opposing the former president in public with the full strength of their personal convictions.</p>
<p>NBC News spoke to more than a half-dozen Iowa voters turned off by Trump — but some were anxious about talking on the record out of fear of being shunned by friends or family. One Iowan said they plan on saying they caucused for Trump when asked by members of their community but will actually caucus for Vivek Ramaswamy.</p>
<p>That adds up to signs going unplaced on front lawns, conversations with friends and family about other candidates avoided — and fewer opportunities for opposition to Trump to take hold in different Republican communities.</p>
<p>NBC News first spoke with Clare in a University of Iowa auditorium Aug. 23, the night of the first GOP presidential debate. Fellow College Republicans were reacting to the debate and voicing steadfast support for the GOP candidate who wasn’t on the stage: Trump.</p>
<p>Clare chose to wait until the end of the night, after the rest of his classmates left the auditorium, to share his thoughts.</p>
<p>“I’m just so scared of doing this right now,” he said, fighting back tears. “I want to be able to have my opinions on our politicians, and I want to be able to speak freely about them and people still understand I’m a conservative.”</p>
<p>Clare criticized Trump, particularly for his actions Jan. 6, 2021, saying, “The end of his administration was un-American.” He also said Trump’s supporters are in denial about losing the 2020 election.</p>
<p>“They don’t want to believe he lost the election. It’s hard to swallow. Losing is hard to swallow. But it’s important that when we lose, we recognize that we lost and we think, ‘What can we do better next time to win over Americans?’” Clare said.</p>
<p>Clare was right to expect backlash from speaking out on Trump. After NBC News published the interview with him on a “Meet The Press” social media account, hateful and homophobic comments poured in. Clare said later that a student came up to him at a university event, shoved a phone in his face with the video on it, and asked him why he’s “scared of Trump and not scared of getting AIDS from having gay sex.”</p>
<p>“Say something they disagree with, and they go after your sexuality,” said Clare, who added that he doesn’t regret doing the interview with NBC News. Many of the comments questioned if Clare — who holds a leadership role at the University of Iowa’s College Republican organization, interned for a Republican on Capitol Hill, and is heavily involved in the Johnson County, Iowa, GOP — was truly a Republican.</p>
<p>“I think it shouldn’t be a bad thing for me to say I am conservative and that I think there are other options, and I don’t think that this person is good for our country,” Clare said. But he’s worried those opinions will stunt his own long-term political ambitions.</p>
<p>“If people as powerful and as prominent as members of Congress can be taken down because of their criticisms of one man, what’s stopping that from happening to me?” Clare noted, referring to the Republicans ousted from Congress after voting to impeach Trump.</p>
<p>Trump’s criticism forced several senators and House members into retirement or primary defeat during his first years in office. Later, of the 10 House Republicans who voted to bring impeachment charges against Trump following the Jan. 6 Capitol riot, four retired before facing voters in 2022 and another four lost their next primaries. Only two remain in the House.</p>
<p>In the Senate, three of the seven Republicans who voted to convict Trump have since retired or resigned, and Sen. Mitt Romney of Utah is retiring next year.</p>
<p>Romney recounted to biographer McKay Coppins that Republican members of Congress confided to him they wanted Trump impeached and convicted but would vote against the charges because they were worried about threats to their families.</p>
<p>Full Sen. Mitt Romney: Trump’s campaign one of ‘retribution, anger and hate’<br />
DEC. 10, 202321:03</p>
<p>Former Rep. Liz Cheney of Wyoming, one of the Republicans who lost a 2022 primary after voting to impeach Trump, detailed similar conversations in her new memoir.</p>
<p>Cheney wrote about one colleague that she “absolutely understood his fear” about what would happen if he voted to impeach Trump. But, she continued, “I also thought, ‘Perhaps you need to be in another job.’”</p>
<p>‘It was easier to be quiet about it’</p>
<p>Rank-and-file voters are less prominent and thus less likely to be harassed or threatened, but some of the same worries and experiences remain. Sears, the Republican from Grimes, Iowa, feels Trump doesn’t reflect her values. But that’s an opinion she kept to herself until recently, because of the fear of being cast off by family and friends.</p>
<p>Recommended<br />
HUNTER BIDENFormer Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop<br />
2024 ELECTIONNevada GOP leaders indicted in pro-Trump ‘fake elector’ case still in charge of caucus planning</p>
<p>“Family and people I work with are Trump supporters,” said Sears, describing her hesitancy to speak out about her beliefs.</p>
<p>“I think Trump supporters tried to coerce or bully people into also being Trump supporters. And so it was easier to be quiet about it,” she said.</p>
<p>Spencer, a retiree now living in a nursing home in Decorah, Iowa, says Trump supporters at her previous retirement community created a toxic environment that stopped her and her friends from voicing opinions.</p>
<p>“We were afraid of arguments,” she said. “When you live with that many old people, sometimes they have very strange but very firm thoughts and you better think the way they do,” she said, explaining her silence.</p>
<p>Clare, Sears and Spencer are not the only people who feel this way.</p>
<p>And as Cheney and Romney’s stories demonstrate, social ostracization isn’t limited to just voters who speak out against Trump. Former Rep. Denver Riggleman, a Republican who represented a slice of Virginia from 2019 to 2021, says his mother texted him, “I’m sorry you were ever elected,” after he came out against Trump.</p>
<p>“It was so soul-crushing to have a family member choose Donald Trump over you,” Riggleman continued. He said evangelical Trump supporters in his life saw Trump as being blessed by God. “I was going directly against religious beliefs. And that’s a losing battle.”</p>
<p>It’s now been almost six months since a member of Congress endorsed a non-Trump candidate in the 2024 GOP primary, according to NBC News’ endorsement tracking.</p>
<p>The trend has popped up elsewhere on the 2024 campaign trail, too. When Iowa Gov. Kim Reynolds endorsed Ron DeSantis in November, the Florida governor mentioned in an interview with NBC News that he “had people come to me and say they endorsed [Trump] because of the threats and everything like that” during the campaign.</p>
<p>Trump quickly went after Reynolds after news of her DeSantis endorsement broke, posting on social media that it would “be the end of her political career.”</p>
<p>Iowa Gov. Reynolds endorses Gov. DeSantis for president: Trump ‘can’t win’ in 2024<br />
NOV. 7, 202323:00</p>
<p>‘Vortex of controversy and vilification’</p>
<p>Charlie Sykes was a conservative radio show host in Wisconsin for more than 20 years before Trump burst onto the political scene. Sykes was skeptical and critical of Trump, eventually confronting him in a heated interview about insults Trump hurled at Texas Sen. Ted Cruz’s wife in 2016. But for Sykes, it began to become clear that there was no room anymore for anti-Trump conservatives on talk radio.</p>
<p>“The audience of conservative talk radio began to think that loyalty was required. They wanted conservative media to be a safe space for them,” Sykes said, describing how his role became untenable.</p>
<p>After leaving radio, Sykes didn’t let up on his Trump criticism, which he says got him booted from a think tank and led him to lose friends and become a self-described political orphan. He says his criticism was met with bullying — and he understands why people who don’t work in the public eye might be hesitant to voice their true feelings about Trump.</p>
<p>“I do understand why people in their normal lives don’t want to be caught up in this vortex of controversy and vilification — why they would step back from all of this,” Sykes said.</p>
<p>Another longtime Wisconsin Republican recently detailed one of the results of that pressure.</p>
<p>Former House Speaker Paul Ryan recently spoke on video at an event for Teneo, a global consulting firm where he serves as vice-chair. Ryan said the impulse to avoid getting on the wrong side of angry Trump supporters pushed former colleagues to vote against impeachment even though they wanted Trump gone — and now he thinks there are many who regret those votes.</p>
<p>“They figured, ‘I’m not gonna take this heat and I’m going to vote against this impeachment because he’s gone anyway,’” Ryan said. “But what’s happened is that he’s been resurrected.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/trumps-secret-weapon-consolidating-the-gop-fear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden on Colorado 14th Amendment decision: There’s ‘no question’ Trump ‘supported an insurrection’</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection-2/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The state Supreme Court disqualified former President Donald Trump from Colorado&#8217;s 2024 primary ballot in a bombshell ruling Tuesday. By Kyla Guilfoil and Caroline Kenny President Joe Biden told reporters Wednesday there is “no question” former President Donald Trump supported an insurrection, a day after the Colorado Supreme Court ruled that Trump was disqualified from the state’s 2024 ... <a title="Biden on Colorado 14th Amendment decision: There’s ‘no question’ Trump ‘supported an insurrection’" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection-2/" aria-label="More on Biden on Colorado 14th Amendment decision: There’s ‘no question’ Trump ‘supported an insurrection’">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The state Supreme Court disqualified former President Donald Trump from Colorado&#8217;s 2024 primary ballot in a bombshell ruling Tuesday.</p>
<p>By Kyla Guilfoil and Caroline Kenny</p>
<p>President Joe Biden told reporters Wednesday there is “no question” former President Donald Trump supported an insurrection, a day after the Colorado Supreme Court ruled that Trump was disqualified from the state’s 2024 primary ballot because of his role in the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol.</p>
<p>“Well I think certainly it’s self-evident,&#8221; Biden said. &#8220;You saw it all. Now whether the 14th Amendment applies, I’ll let the court make that decision. But he certainly supported an insurrection.&#8221;</p>
<p>“No question about it — none, zero. And he seems to be doubling down on everything,” the president added.</p>
<p>In its ruling Tuesday, the Colorado Supreme Court declared that the former president “is disqualified from holding the office of President under Section Three of the Fourteenth Amendment of the United States Constitution,” and thus should not be on the state’s primary ballot next year.</p>
<p>Biden weighs in after Colorado’s Supreme Court removes Trump from 2024 ballot<br />
DEC. 21, 202303:39</p>
<p>The bombshell ruling is the first of its kind, finding its basis in a lawsuit that focused on a little-known provision in the 14th Amendment. None of numerous similar challenges in other states have been successful so far.</p>
<p>The Colorado Supreme Court explicitly included in its opinion that that state&#8217;s secretary of state, Jena Griswold, “may not list President Trump’s name on the 2024 presidential primary ballot, nor may she count any write-in votes cast for him.”</p>
<p>Recommended<br />
HUNTER BIDENFormer Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop<br />
2024 ELECTIONNevada GOP leaders indicted in pro-Trump ‘fake elector’ case still in charge of caucus planning</p>
<p>Biden has repeatedly called Trump and his “Make America Great Again” following a threat to democracy following the Jan. 6 attack.</p>
<p>In September, the president warned in a speech that Trump believes presidents possess fearsome, unchecked powers, citing a quote from Trump in 2019 in which the then-president described Article II of the Constitution as giving him &#8220;the right to do whatever I want as president.&#8221; That view is at odds with constitutional norms meant to prevent unilateral rule.</p>
<p>A year before, Biden likened “MAGA philosophy” to &#8220;semi-fascism,” while speaking at a midterm election fundraiser in August 2022.</p>
<p>“What we’re seeing now is the beginning or the death knell of an extreme MAGA philosophy,&#8221; Biden said at the event. &#8220;It’s not just Trump, it’s the entire philosophy that underpins the — I’m going to say something, it’s like semi-fascism.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden on Colorado 14th Amendment decision: There’s ‘no question’ Trump ‘supported an insurrection’</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The state Supreme Court disqualified former President Donald Trump from Colorado&#8217;s 2024 primary ballot in a bombshell ruling Tuesday. By Kyla Guilfoil and Caroline Kenny President Joe Biden told reporters Wednesday there is “no question” former President Donald Trump supported an insurrection, a day after the Colorado Supreme Court ruled that Trump was disqualified from the state’s 2024 ... <a title="Biden on Colorado 14th Amendment decision: There’s ‘no question’ Trump ‘supported an insurrection’" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection/" aria-label="More on Biden on Colorado 14th Amendment decision: There’s ‘no question’ Trump ‘supported an insurrection’">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The state Supreme Court disqualified former President Donald Trump from Colorado&#8217;s 2024 primary ballot in a bombshell ruling Tuesday.</p>
<p>By Kyla Guilfoil and Caroline Kenny</p>
<p>President Joe Biden told reporters Wednesday there is “no question” former President Donald Trump supported an insurrection, a day after the Colorado Supreme Court ruled that Trump was disqualified from the state’s 2024 primary ballot because of his role in the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol.</p>
<p>“Well I think certainly it’s self-evident,&#8221; Biden said. &#8220;You saw it all. Now whether the 14th Amendment applies, I’ll let the court make that decision. But he certainly supported an insurrection.&#8221;</p>
<p>“No question about it — none, zero. And he seems to be doubling down on everything,” the president added.</p>
<p>In its ruling Tuesday, the Colorado Supreme Court declared that the former president “is disqualified from holding the office of President under Section Three of the Fourteenth Amendment of the United States Constitution,” and thus should not be on the state’s primary ballot next year.</p>
<p>Biden weighs in after Colorado’s Supreme Court removes Trump from 2024 ballot<br />
DEC. 21, 202303:39</p>
<p>The bombshell ruling is the first of its kind, finding its basis in a lawsuit that focused on a little-known provision in the 14th Amendment. None of numerous similar challenges in other states have been successful so far.</p>
<p>The Colorado Supreme Court explicitly included in its opinion that that state&#8217;s secretary of state, Jena Griswold, “may not list President Trump’s name on the 2024 presidential primary ballot, nor may she count any write-in votes cast for him.”</p>
<p>Recommended<br />
HUNTER BIDENFormer Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop<br />
2024 ELECTIONNevada GOP leaders indicted in pro-Trump ‘fake elector’ case still in charge of caucus planning</p>
<p>Biden has repeatedly called Trump and his “Make America Great Again” following a threat to democracy following the Jan. 6 attack.</p>
<p>In September, the president warned in a speech that Trump believes presidents possess fearsome, unchecked powers, citing a quote from Trump in 2019 in which the then-president described Article II of the Constitution as giving him &#8220;the right to do whatever I want as president.&#8221; That view is at odds with constitutional norms meant to prevent unilateral rule.</p>
<p>A year before, Biden likened “MAGA philosophy” to &#8220;semi-fascism,” while speaking at a midterm election fundraiser in August 2022.</p>
<p>“What we’re seeing now is the beginning or the death knell of an extreme MAGA philosophy,&#8221; Biden said at the event. &#8220;It’s not just Trump, it’s the entire philosophy that underpins the — I’m going to say something, it’s like semi-fascism.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/biden-on-colorado-14th-amendment-decision-theres-no-question-trump-supported-an-insurrection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Records released by House Republicans show that Joe Biden repeatedly emailed Hunter Biden’s business associate in 2014</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/records-released-by-house-republicans-show-that-joe-biden-repeatedly-emailed-hunter-bidens-business-associate-in-2014/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/records-released-by-house-republicans-show-that-joe-biden-repeatedly-emailed-hunter-bidens-business-associate-in-2014/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Democrats say the emails were routine and that Hunter Biden’s business associate worked as Joe Biden’s financial adviser and helped the then-vice president file his tax returns. By Tom Winter Joe Biden exchanged emails with his son Hunter’s business associate 54 times while he was serving as vice president, and some of the messages were sent around ... <a title="Records released by House Republicans show that Joe Biden repeatedly emailed Hunter Biden’s business associate in 2014" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/records-released-by-house-republicans-show-that-joe-biden-repeatedly-emailed-hunter-bidens-business-associate-in-2014/" aria-label="More on Records released by House Republicans show that Joe Biden repeatedly emailed Hunter Biden’s business associate in 2014">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrats say the emails were routine and that Hunter Biden’s business associate worked as Joe Biden’s financial adviser and helped the then-vice president file his tax returns.</p>
<p>By Tom Winter</p>
<p>Joe Biden exchanged emails with his son Hunter’s business associate 54 times while he was serving as vice president, and some of the messages were sent around the time the elder Biden was traveling to Ukraine and his son was working for a Ukrainian gas company, according to records released by House Republicans.</p>
<p>A White House spokesperson declined to comment but pointed to statements by House Democrats that Hunter Biden’s business associate, Eric Schwerin, worked as Joe Biden’s financial adviser from 2009 to 2017 and helped him file his tax returns. Schwerin did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<p>The records released describe the dates of the emails and who exchanged them, but do not include the messages themselves. NBC News has not reviewed the contents of the emails.</p>
<p>All told, then-Vice President Biden emailed Schwerin 35 times before and after his 2014 trips to Ukraine. Five emails were exchanged just prior to a trip by Vice President Biden to Ukraine on June 7, 2014, and 27 emails were sent from the end of June to a second trip to Ukraine by Biden on Nov. 21, 2014.</p>
<p>The bulk of the communication occurred in the lead-up to and following an agreement for Hunter Biden to serve on the board of the Ukrainian natural gas company Burisma.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Rep. Jamie Raskin, D-Md., said in a news release that Schwerin told House Ways and Means Committee staff in a March interview that the elder Biden was not involved in the business of his son or any of his relatives.</p>
<p>Raskin said Schwerin stated that “he was not aware of any involvement by President Biden in the financial conduct of the President’s relatives’ businesses, much less any transactions into or out of the then-vice president’s bank account related to business conducted by any Biden family member.”</p>
<p>The email disclosures were part of law enforcement records released by House Republicans following the testimony of IRS whistleblower Joseph Ziegler. This month, Ziegler provided the documents to the House Ways and Means Committee in conjunction with a sworn affidavit. The committee, which also heard the testimony of a second IRS whistleblower, Gary Shapley, is led by Rep. Jason Smith, R-Mo.</p>
<p>Ziegler told Congress that “there were multiple emails found with Hunter Biden and his business associates” but the investigative team was unaware at the time that then-Vice President Biden used an alias in his private emails.</p>
<p>Recommended<br />
U.S. NEWSBody found in trunk of burning car in California<br />
#METOO RECKONINGLawsuit alleges Vin Diesel sexually assaulted his assistant in 2010</p>
<p>Hunter Biden earned nearly $1.2 million from Burisma in 2014, according to emails contained on a copy of his hard drive and obtained by NBC News. In their recent tax indictment of Biden, federal prosecutors alleged he made over $1.4 million from 2016 to 2019, when Biden’s engagement with the Ukrainian firm ended.</p>
<p>Biden is scheduled to be arraigned on misdemeanor and felony federal tax charges in Los Angeles in early January. After his indictment last week, Biden’s attorney Abbe Lowell said in a statement, “After five years of investigating with no new evidence — and two years after Hunter paid his taxes in full — the U.S. Attorney has piled on nine new charges when he had agreed just months ago to resolve this matter with a pair of misdemeanors.”</p>
<p>Biden’s addition to Burisma’s board as head of legal affairs was reported in a news release in May 2014. At some point from May to December 2014, Burisma allegedly paid a bribe to a Ukrainian official to help stop a joint British-U.S. money-laundering investigation into Burisma’s top executive, according to a State Department email that quotes a Ukrainian prosecutor.</p>
<p>Former President Donald Trump has falsely claimed that Joe Biden helped oust a Ukrainian prosecutor, Victor Shokin, when he was “prosecuting” Burisma. Multiple U.S. officials testified to Congress that Shokin was forced out in a joint American and British effort because he himself was corrupt.</p>
<p>Hunter Biden later wrote in his 2021 book, &#8220;Beautiful Things: A Memoir,&#8221; that few of his business deals brought tangible results. He said he wasn’t “desperate” before he landed a position on the board of Burisma in 2014 but that the money was “helpful” and that it came at a “fortuitous” time.</p>
<p>He said it meant he didn’t have to work hard to find clients, “the most time-consuming part of my work — drilling twenty dry wells to finally hit pay dirt,” and that it allowed him to spend more time with his dying brother, Beau.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/records-released-by-house-republicans-show-that-joe-biden-repeatedly-emailed-hunter-bidens-business-associate-in-2014/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liberals seek ouster from Wisconsin judicial ethics panel of Trump lawyer who advised fake electors</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/liberals-seek-ouster-from-wisconsin-judicial-ethics-panel-of-trump-lawyer-who-advised-fake-electors/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/liberals-seek-ouster-from-wisconsin-judicial-ethics-panel-of-trump-lawyer-who-advised-fake-electors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jim Troupis, a former judge, was deeply involved in Trump’s efforts to overturn Wisconsin’s 2020 election results. By Associated Press MADISON, Wis. — Liberals are calling for former President Donald Trump’s Wisconsin lawyer to step down from a state judicial ethics panel, saying he is unsuitable due to his role advising the fake Republican electors who ... <a title="Liberals seek ouster from Wisconsin judicial ethics panel of Trump lawyer who advised fake electors" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/liberals-seek-ouster-from-wisconsin-judicial-ethics-panel-of-trump-lawyer-who-advised-fake-electors/" aria-label="More on Liberals seek ouster from Wisconsin judicial ethics panel of Trump lawyer who advised fake electors">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jim Troupis, a former judge, was deeply involved in Trump’s efforts to overturn Wisconsin’s 2020 election results.</p>
<p>By Associated Press</p>
<p>MADISON, Wis. — Liberals are calling for former President Donald Trump’s Wisconsin lawyer to step down from a state judicial ethics panel, saying he is unsuitable due to his role advising the fake Republican electors who admitted to taking part in an effort to overturn the 2020 election.</p>
<p>Jim Troupis, a former judge, was deeply involved in Trump’s efforts to overturn Wisconsin’s 2020 election results. He remains a defendant in a lawsuit filed against him, Trump’s attorney Ken Chesebro and the 10 fake Republican electors.</p>
<p>The electors agreed to a settlement in the lawsuit, but Troupis and Chesebro remain defendants.</p>
<p>Troupis has been a member of the Judicial Conduct Advisory Committee since 2020. The committee is charged with giving formal opinions and informal advice to judges and judicial officers related to the code of judicial conduct. The advice involves whether possible actions would be in compliance with the state’s judicial code of conduct.</p>
<p>The committee rarely issues formal written opinions and has not issued one since 2019, according to its website.</p>
<p>Troupis’s place on the panel advising judges about possible ethical violations is improper given his involvement with the fake elector scheme, said Mike Browne, deputy director of the liberal advocacy group One Wisconsin Now.</p>
<p>“He never should have been reappointed after his role in the MAGA conspiracy to undermine our freedom was public,” Browne said in a statement, referring to the Trump campaign slogan “Make America great again.”</p>
<p>“And he certainly shouldn’t continue to serve in any position of public trust now. If he doesn’t have the decency to step down on his own, the right-wing justices who wrongly supported his re-appointment should step in and remove him,” Browne said.</p>
<p>Calls for Troupis to be replaced on the judicial commission echo those from Democrats who want one of the fake electors, Bob Spindell, to be removed from the bipartisan state elections commission. But the Republican Senate majority leader who appointed Spindell has refused to rescind the appointment.</p>
<p>Troupis was reappointed to serve on the judicial ethics panel in March by four conservative members of the Wisconsin Supreme Court, including three who remain on the court.</p>
<p>Neither Troupis nor the justices who appointed him — Chief Justice Annette Ziegler and justices Rebecca Bradley and Brian Hagedorn — replied to messages seeking comment.</p>
<p>Recommended<br />
HUNTER BIDENFormer Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop<br />
2024 ELECTIONNevada GOP leaders indicted in pro-Trump ‘fake elector’ case still in charge of caucus planning</p>
<p>Winnebago County Circuit Judge Bryan Keberlein, who chairs the judicial advisory committee, was not available for comment.</p>
<p>President Joe Biden won Wisconsin in 2020. Trump’s campaign tried to overturn the results by arguing, in lawsuits filed by Troupis, that tens of thousands of absentee ballots legally cast should not have counted. The Wisconsin Supreme Court rejected the Trump lawsuit on a 4-3 ruling, upholding Biden’s win.</p>
<p>In addition to the lawsuits, Troupis also was involved with the fake elector scheme in Wisconsin.</p>
<p>Fake electors in Wisconsin and six other battleground states sent certificates to Congress falsely declaring Trump the winner of the 2020 presidential election, despite confirmed results showing he had lost.</p>
<p>The scheme began in Wisconsin, according to prosecutors who brought a four-count indictment released against Trump in August.</p>
<p>Chesebro wrote in a Dec. 13, 2020, email that the strategy “was not to use the fraudulent electors only in the circumstance that the Defendant’s litigation was successful in one of the targeted states.” Instead, he wrote, “the plan was to falsely present the fraudulent slates as an alternative to the legitimate slates at Congress’s certification proceeding.”</p>
<p>The Georgia indictment of Trump refers to Chesebro’s memo to Troupis as an “overt act in furtherance of the conspiracy.”</p>
<p>After Wisconsin’s fake electors met on Dec. 14, 2020, Troupis contacted U.S. Sen. Ron Johnson’s staff and asked that Johnson deliver the documents from the fake electors in Wisconsin and Michigan to Vice President Mike Pence. A Pence staff member refused to accept them.</p>
<p>On Dec. 6, Nevada became the third state to charge electors, following Michigan and Georgia. Wisconsin Democratic Attorney General Josh Kaul has repeatedly refused to say whether there is an ongoing criminal investigation related to the state’s fake electors, Troupis and Chesebro.</p>
<p>In the recent legal settlement, the 10 fake electors admitted Biden had won the election and their efforts were part of an attempt to improperly overturn the 2020 results. Under the deal, the fake electors didn’t pay any damages or attorneys fees, or admit wrongdoing or liability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/liberals-seek-ouster-from-wisconsin-judicial-ethics-panel-of-trump-lawyer-who-advised-fake-electors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/former-trump-aide-asks-judge-to-dismiss-hunter-biden-lawsuit-tied-to-laptop/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/former-trump-aide-asks-judge-to-dismiss-hunter-biden-lawsuit-tied-to-laptop/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden claimed in the suit that Garrett Ziegler and his company broke the law in an effort to create an online database with emails attributed to him. By Gary Grumbach and Zoë Richards A former Trump White House aide has asked a federal judge to dismiss a lawsuit that alleged he violated state and federal laws in connection ... <a title="Former Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/former-trump-aide-asks-judge-to-dismiss-hunter-biden-lawsuit-tied-to-laptop/" aria-label="More on Former Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden claimed in the suit that Garrett Ziegler and his company broke the law in an effort to create an online database with emails attributed to him.</p>
<section class="mb7">
<div class="article-inline-byline" data-activity-map="inline-byline-article-top">By <span class="byline-name" data-testid="byline-name">Gary Grumbach</span> and <span class="byline-name" data-testid="byline-name">Zoë Richards</span></div>
</section>
<div class="article-body__content">
<p class="">A former Trump White House aide has asked a federal judge to dismiss a lawsuit that alleged he violated state and federal laws in connection with the online publication of laptop content attributed to Hunter Biden.</p>
<p class="">The president’s son sued Garrett Ziegler and his company, Marco Polo, in September, claiming they broke state and federal laws in an effort to create an online searchable database with 128,000 emails attributed to Biden.</p>
<p class="">Attorneys for Ziegler, who worked on trade policy in the White House under Trump adviser Peter Navarro, argued in a 30-page filing that Biden’s legal team had not established a causal connection between Ziegler’s conduct and Biden’s claims of injury related to the data and that they failed to state &#8220;a viable claim.&#8221;</p>
<p class="">“Plaintiff alleges no facts which demonstrate Defendants ever accessed any computer, storage, or service which Plaintiff either owns or has exclusive control over,” Ziegler&#8217;s attorneys wrote in a filing with a federal court in the Central District of California.</p>
<p class="">In their lawsuit, Biden&#8217;s attorneys had acknowledged that &#8220;the precise manner by which Defendant Ziegler obtained Plaintiff’s data remains unclear&#8221; but said it was indisputable that Ziegler and his company had &#8220;to at least some extent, accessed, tampered with, manipulated, altered, copied and damaged&#8221; data attributed to Biden in a manner that was illegal and without his consent.</p>
<div class="recommended-intersection-ref" data-activity-map="recommended-article-body-recommended" data-testid="recommended-wrapper">
<div>
<section class="related dn-print" data-testid="related" aria-label="Related content">
<h3 class="related__title">Recommended</h3>
<div id="recommended" class="related__items">
<div class="related-item">
<div class="related-item__info-wrapper">
<h3 class="related-item__title"><span class="related-item__eyebrow">2024 ELECTION</span>Nevada GOP leaders indicted in pro-Trump ‘fake elector’ case still in charge of caucus planning</h3>
</div>
</div>
<div class="related-item">
<div class="related-item__info-wrapper">
<h3 class="related-item__title"><span class="related-item__eyebrow">2024 ELECTION</span>Man charged with threatening to kill Vivek Ramaswamy is indicted over threats to other candidates</h3>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</div>
</div>
<p class="">Ziegler’s legal team also argued that First Amendment protections apply in the case. His attorneys said Ziegler and his company’s conduct “constitutes protected activity because it involves a public figure and is a matter of public importance.”</p>
<p class="">An attorney for Biden did not immediately respond to a request for comment Thursday night.</p>
<p class="">Separate from the lawsuit, Biden faces a pair of indictments stemming from a federal investigation. He pleaded not guilty to a three-count indictment tied to his alleged possession of a gun while he was using narcotics, and he was indicted this month on nine tax-related charges, including three felony counts. An arraignment in that case is scheduled for January.</p>
<p class="endmark">House Republicans have also targeted Biden in their impeachment inquiry into President Joe Biden. The president&#8217;s son recently defied a congressional subpoena that requested a closed-door deposition. He instead offered to testify publicly, saying that would ensure that the Republican-led investigations &#8220;do not proceed on distortions, manipulated evidence and lies.”</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/former-trump-aide-asks-judge-to-dismiss-hunter-biden-lawsuit-tied-to-laptop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>House Speaker Mike Johnson calls on Biden to take executive actions on the border</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/house-speaker-mike-johnson-calls-on-biden-to-take-executive-actions-on-the-border/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/house-speaker-mike-johnson-calls-on-biden-to-take-executive-actions-on-the-border/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Republican speaker&#8217;s letter comes as Congress left for the year without an agreement to address the border crisis and CBP saw record migrant apprehensions. By Scott Wong, Peter Nicholas and Monica Alba WASHINGTON — With Congress gone for the year with no border deal, House Speaker Mike Johnson, R-La., on Thursday sent a scathing letter to President Joe Biden, blaming him for the ... <a title="House Speaker Mike Johnson calls on Biden to take executive actions on the border" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/house-speaker-mike-johnson-calls-on-biden-to-take-executive-actions-on-the-border/" aria-label="More on House Speaker Mike Johnson calls on Biden to take executive actions on the border">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Republican speaker&#8217;s letter comes as Congress left for the year without an agreement to address the border crisis and CBP saw record migrant apprehensions.</p>
<section class="mb7">
<div class="article-inline-byline" data-activity-map="inline-byline-article-top">By <span class="byline-name" data-testid="byline-name">Scott Wong</span>, <span class="byline-name" data-testid="byline-name">Peter Nicholas</span> and <span class="byline-name" data-testid="byline-name">Monica Alba</span></div>
</section>
<div class="article-body__content">
<p class="">WASHINGTON — With Congress gone for the year with no border deal, House Speaker Mike Johnson, R-La., on Thursday sent a scathing letter to President Joe Biden, blaming him for the border crisis and urging him to take a number of executive actions “to stem the record tide of illegal immigration.”</p>
<p class="">Those executive actions, Johnson said, include ending the policy allowing Customs and Border Protection to release migrants without court dates, and “turnback or detain all aliens encountered between ports of entry”; restricting parole, which allows the president to temporarily admit some migrants; and pursuing agreements with third countries like Canada to take those seeking asylum in the U.S.</p>
<div id="taboolaReadMoreBelow"></div>
<p class="">Johnson also urged Biden to resume construction of the border wall.</p>
<p class="">“While a bipartisan group of Senators has begun extensive negotiations over the past few weeks to try to find a compromise, they have not yet been able to finalize an agreement,” Johnson wrote. “Statutory reforms designed to restore operational control at our southern border must be enacted, but the crisis at our southern border has deteriorated to such an extent that significant action can wait no longer.</p>
<p class="">“It must start now, and it must start with you,” the speaker said.</p>
<section class="inline-video inline-video--in-body" data-testid="inline-video">
<div class="inline-video__info">
<h2 class="inline-video__title">Biden needs to do a ‘better job’ with outreach to Latinos, says Congressional Hispanic Caucus chair</h2>
<p><span class="inline-video__detail">DEC. 21, 202306:05</span></p>
<div class="styles_share__n3Syu inline-video__share dn-print">
<div class="styles_shareList___M8wC inline-video__share-list"></div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<p class="">Johnson’s letter comes as recent video footage shows CBP being overwhelmed by migrants trying to cross the southern border with Mexico. A new record was set just this week when CBP apprehended more than 12,000 migrants in a single day on the southwest border, nearly 11,000 of whom are migrants who crossed the border illegally between ports of entry, Department of Homeland Security officials said.</p>
<p class="">Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas and other Biden administration officials have been closely working with a trio of senators trying to negotiate a border agreement that’s needed to unlock aid for Ukraine and Israel. Sens. Chris Murphy, D-Conn.; James Lankford, R-Okla.; and Kyrsten Sinema, I-Ariz., held their final in-person talks in the Capitol on Wednesday, but they said they were making progress and that virtual negotiations would continue during the holiday break.</p>
<p class="">&#8220;Obviously we are part of these negotiations with the senators; we think it’s going in the right direction. We want to make sure we get to a bipartisan agreement,&#8221; White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said at her daily briefing Thursday. &#8220;The president understands, he understands that we have to fix this immigration system — it’s been broken for decades now.”</p>
<p class="">Jean-Pierre said she had not yet reviewed Johnson&#8217;s letter but noted that the Biden administration had added 24,000 Border Patrol agents this year and is engaged in diplomatic talks with Mexican President Andrés Manuel López Obrador and other leaders to deal with the surge of migrants.</p>
<p class="">&#8220;The president has done everything that he can, right, on his own,&#8221; she said.</p>
<div class="recommended-intersection-ref" data-activity-map="recommended-article-body-recommended" data-testid="recommended-wrapper">
<div>
<section class="related dn-print" data-testid="related" aria-label="Related content">
<h3 class="related__title">Recommended</h3>
<div id="recommended" class="related__items">
<div class="related-item">
<div class="related-item__info-wrapper">
<h3 class="related-item__title"><span class="related-item__eyebrow">HUNTER BIDEN</span>Former Trump aide asks judge to dismiss Hunter Biden lawsuit tied to laptop</h3>
</div>
</div>
<div class="related-item">
<div class="related-item__thumbnail-wrapper"></div>
<div class="related-item__info-wrapper">
<h3 class="related-item__title"><span class="related-item__eyebrow">2024 ELECTION</span>Nevada GOP leaders indicted in pro-Trump ‘fake elector’ case still in charge of caucus planning</h3>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</div>
</div>
<p class="">Responding directly to Johnson’s letter, White House spokesperson Angelo Fernández Hernández said House Republicans voted against Biden’s request for funding to hire more Border Patrol agents, pushed for a stopgap funding bill that would have cut 800 CBP agents, and failed to take up the president’s supplemental request in October that calls for more border security funding.</p>
<p class="">Jean-Pierre said she had no information about a potential one-on-one meeting between Biden and Johnson in the new year, or why that had not happened yet. Shortly after he was elected speaker in October, Johnson attended a meeting at the White House where the president stopped by. Aides to Biden and Johnson also have been in touch, Jean-Pierre said Thursday.</p>
<p class="">In his letter, copies of which were sent to Mayorkas and the three congressional leaders, Johnson said the border crisis “has caused unspeakable human tragedy for migrants and certainly for our own citizens.” He pointed to record amounts of fentanyl being seized at the border, saying that “fentanyl poisoning is now the leading cause of death for Americans aged 18- 45.” And because criminals have illegally entered the U.S., the speaker said, “We are now more vulnerable to a terrorist attack on our homeland than ever.”</p>
<p class="">Johnson laid blame squarely at the feet of the president.</p>
<p class="endmark">“All of this is the direct result of your administration’s policies,” he said. “You have clearly undermined America’s sovereignty and security by ending the Remain in Mexico policy, reinstating catch-and-release, suspending asylum cooperative agreements with other nations, revoking existing restraints on the abuse of parole, and halting border wall construction.”</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/house-speaker-mike-johnson-calls-on-biden-to-take-executive-actions-on-the-border/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spokane Valley City Council debates employee pay hikes for 2024</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/spokane-valley-city-council-debates-employee-pay-hikes-for-2024/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/spokane-valley-city-council-debates-employee-pay-hikes-for-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(The Center Square) – After extended discussion Tuesday evening, Spokane Valley City Council members approved a 3% wage increase for employees that takes effect in 2024. Human resources director John Whitehead initially suggested a 2.5% pay hike and job grade adjustment by the same amount for regular city staff beginning Jan. 1. Whitehead said inflation ... <a title="Spokane Valley City Council debates employee pay hikes for 2024" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/spokane-valley-city-council-debates-employee-pay-hikes-for-2024/" aria-label="More on Spokane Valley City Council debates employee pay hikes for 2024">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(The Center Square) – After extended discussion Tuesday evening, Spokane Valley City Council members approved a 3% wage increase for employees that takes effect in 2024.</p>
<p>Human resources director John Whitehead initially suggested a 2.5% pay hike and job grade adjustment by the same amount for regular city staff beginning Jan. 1. Whitehead said inflation had “eroded” workers’ wages and that an increase would help in retaining and recruiting qualified employees.</p>
<p>Councilman Tim Hattenburg said the suggested increase was still below the current rate of inflation – 3.4% was cited – and he proposed a 3% pay raise instead.</p>
<p>In response, fellow councilman Ben Wick voiced concern about impacts to the 2024 budget, which will fund 116 full time-equivalent employees.</p>
<p>Wick said the city has “some amazing individuals on staff” and that he appreciated their hard work. “But we do have some budget pressures,” said Wick, referring to rising costs in other areas including significant increases in new parks maintenance contracts.</p>
<p>Whitehead said increasing from 2.5% to 3% would cost the city an estimated $70,000 in additional expense next year.</p>
<p>Council member Brandi Peetz asked, “Where do we get the money to do that?”</p>
<p>Finance director Chelsie Taylor said the city’s capital reserve fund has about $4 million available, although those monies are typically used for one-time projects.</p>
<p>“We do have room in the recurring budget,” she told the council, but added that any continuing use “would be a future concern.”</p>
<div id="tncms-region-article_instory_middle" class="tncms-region hidden-print"></div>
<p>“This is tough,” said Peetz, who also called city staff “amazing” but questioned if an additional 0.5% increase would provide much economic help after taxes and whether the money would be better spent on facilities which benefit employees.</p>
<p>Councilman Arne Woodard and mayor Pam Haley both echoed Whitehead’s comments on the need for a wage scale that serves to both recruit and retain employees. Haley supported the 3% increase, saying it would not match the current inflation rate “but it’s close.”</p>
<p>“I would give more if I could,” said the mayor, lauding Spokane Valley employees for productivity comparable to other cities around the state with much-larger staffs.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the 3% pay increase was approved in a 5-2 vote, with Haley, Hattenburg, Woodard, Peetz and deputy Rod Higgins in support. Wick and council member Laura Padden dissented.</p>
<p>During an earlier public comment period, a few citizens suggested using the $70,000 difference as a start in adding to the city’s police force.</p>
<p>Haley said the annual cost to fund one officer’s position is double that amount, and that the council and city administrators have been working with the police department to add personnel in the future.</p>
<p>“We love cops,” said Woodard, but added that bolstering the police department will be an “incremental” process.</p>
<p>In November, city staff recommended increasing personnel in the police force, but no cost figures were factored into the 2024 budget as adopted. At the time, deputy city manager Erik Lamb said costs should be part of a “comprehensive discussion” involving the council and police chief Dave Ellis to determine the department’s immediate and long-term staffing needs, expenses, and revenue sources.</p>
<p>The council’s Dec. 19 meeting agenda and video can be viewed <strong>here</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/spokane-valley-city-council-debates-employee-pay-hikes-for-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#8217;s Go Washington submits 857K signatures to repeal capital gains tax, ban new income tax</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/lets-go-washington-submits-857k-signatures-to-repeal-capital-gains-tax-ban-new-income-tax/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/lets-go-washington-submits-857k-signatures-to-repeal-capital-gains-tax-ban-new-income-tax/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(The Center Square) – It wasn’t Santa Claus delivering Christmas presents, but on Thursday afternoon, voter advocacy group Let’s Go Washington turned in 419,699 signatures for Initiative 2109, which would repeal the capital gains tax, and 437,960 signatures for Initiative 2111, which would prohibit income taxes at the city and county level. “It’s a lot,” ... <a title="Let&#8217;s Go Washington submits 857K signatures to repeal capital gains tax, ban new income tax" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/lets-go-washington-submits-857k-signatures-to-repeal-capital-gains-tax-ban-new-income-tax/" aria-label="More on Let&#8217;s Go Washington submits 857K signatures to repeal capital gains tax, ban new income tax">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(The Center Square) – It wasn’t Santa Claus delivering Christmas presents, but on Thursday afternoon, voter advocacy group Let’s Go Washington turned in 419,699 signatures for Initiative 2109, which would repeal the capital gains tax, and 437,960 signatures for Initiative 2111, which would prohibit income taxes at the city and county level.</p>
<p>“It’s a lot,” deadpanned Glen Morgan, founder of the “We The Governed” website, when asked to comment on the turn-in of signatures at the Secretary of State’s office in Tumwater.</p>
<p>Let’s Go Washington founder Brian Heywood of Redmond spoke about his motivation for the two initiatives.</p>
<div class="tnt-ads-container text-center">
<div id="tnt-smart-ad-1" class="tnt-ads dfp-smart-ad" data-google-query-id="CP2hlKbgooMDFUEBtwAdQ6sO8g">
<p>“Why am I doing this?” he asked. “Because I grew up poor. I grew up poor in Arizona, and I believe…that the ‘American Dream’ is real and it’s the coolest freakin’ thing on Earth. It doesn’t matter where you’re born or how poor you are or what station in life or what your status is, if you want to, you can find opportunities in this fantastic country to do things that no one else can do and you can change your station.”</p>
<p>Washington voters have directly voted down an income tax 10 times at the ballot box over the past 100 years, in 1934, 1936, 1938, 1942, 1944, 1970, 1973, 1975, 1982 and 2010.</p>
<p>“How many times do voters need to tell lawmakers to stop with income taxes once and for all?” Heywood said. “Once politicians’ budgets take a hit from people like Bezos taking their money to Florida, who do you think will be the target of the next big tax? Small business owners, homeowners, young entrepreneurs, hard-working restaurant and family farm employers and regular, hardworking taxpayers.”</p>
<p>Heywood was making reference to billionaire Amazon founder Jeff Bezos announcing in November that he plans to <strong>move</strong> from Washington to Florida to be closer to his parents.</p>
<p>In January 2022, Washington implemented a 7% tax on the sale of financial assets despite a legal challenge. Earlier this year, the state Supreme Court upheld the constitutionality of the capital gains tax.</p>
<p>“Well, I mean this is a Christmas present for all taxpayers of Washington state,” initiatives sponsor Rep. Jim Walsh, R-Aberdeen, and chair of the Washington State Republican Party, told The Center Square.</p>
<p>He said ordinary people aren’t buying the narrative of the capital gains tax proponents that the rich aren’t paying their fair share of taxes.</p>
<p>“They know the capital gains tax is an income tax, and they know there’s a slippery slope,” Walsh continued. “They’re going to keep a high threshold initially.”</p>
<p>That’s a reference to at least one Democrat – Sen. Jamie Pedersen, D-Seattle – saying in emails and at at least one public meeting that he would like to <strong>leverage</strong> a capital gains tax into a general income tax in Washington.</p>
<p>Invest in Washington Now, which describes itself as a progressive revenue solutions organization, decried the signature-gathering efforts.</p>
<p>“I-2109 would repeal the capital gains tax on the super-rich, taking more than $900 million from education and child care funding to line the pockets of WA’s wealthiest,” Invest in Washington Now Executive Director Treasure Mackley said in an email blast.</p>
<p>She went on to claim, “I-2111 would slash benefits that Washingtonians are counting on, like paid family leave and long-term care benefits.”</p>
<p>Initiatives are required to receive nearly 325,000 verified signatures to qualify for the ballot.</p>
<p>Assuming the two initiatives qualify with enough valid signatures, lawmakers in the Democratic-controlled Legislature have several options: pass them during the upcoming legislative session; take no action and let them go to the ballot; or pass alternative proposals, which would see both initiatives and the alternative proposals placed on the ballot at the next state general election in 2024.</p>
<p>Let’s Go Washington has previously turned in signatures for initiatives to repeal Washington’s cap-and-trade program; provide parents and guardians with a right to review educational materials, receive certain notifications, and opt out of certain sexual health education programs; and remove certain restrictions on police officers’ ability to engage in vehicular pursuits.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/lets-go-washington-submits-857k-signatures-to-repeal-capital-gains-tax-ban-new-income-tax/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nine Kinds of Ancestors You Could Find on Your Family Tree</title>
		<link>/2023/12/22/nine-kinds-of-ancestors-you-could-find-on-your-family-tree/</link>
					<comments>/2023/12/22/nine-kinds-of-ancestors-you-could-find-on-your-family-tree/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 09:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FAMILY HISTORY 20 August 2019 BY JESSICA MORGAN Family trees often have a kaleidoscope of different people who led fascinating, inspiring, and sometimes heartbreaking lives. If you’d like an idea of the many types ancestors you can discover on your tree, here’s a list of nine kinds of ancestors frequently found in family trees. Also check ... <a title="Nine Kinds of Ancestors You Could Find on Your Family Tree" class="read-more" href="/2023/12/22/nine-kinds-of-ancestors-you-could-find-on-your-family-tree/" aria-label="More on Nine Kinds of Ancestors You Could Find on Your Family Tree">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>FAMILY HISTORY<br />
20 August 2019<br />
BY JESSICA MORGAN</p>
<p>Family trees often have a kaleidoscope of different people who led fascinating, inspiring, and sometimes heartbreaking lives. If you’d like an idea of the many types ancestors you can discover on your tree, here’s a list of nine kinds of ancestors frequently found in family trees.</p>
<p>Also check out the Ancestry collections below, which can start you on the road of discovery for your ancestor’s story.</p>
<p>1. Irish Famine Immigrant</p>
<p>The Irish Potato Famine started in 1845. In less than five years, more than a million Irish people died of starvation. About a million more immigrated to England, Canada, Australia, and America to escape the famine.</p>
<p>Today many people around the world can trace their ancestry back to Ireland. Notable people like John F. Kennedy, Walt Disney, and George Clooney all have Irish ancestors.</p>
<p>Do you have an ancestor who escaped the Famine? Look at these collections in your quest to find out:</p>
<p>Searching for Missing Friends: Irish Immigrant Advertisements Placed in “The Boston Pilot,’ 1831-1920<br />
New York, Passenger and Crew Lists (including Castle Garden and Ellis Island), 1820-1957<br />
2. Revolutionary War Soldier</p>
<p>Throughout the Revolutionary War, about 230,000 soldiers and 145,000 militiamen (i.e. non-professional combatants) served in the Continental Army. Any able male between ages 16 and 55 could enlist, and was paid $6-8 per month.</p>
<p>Those who fought in the Continental Army came from many backgrounds, from English merchants to German farmers to African Americans hoping to win their freedom.</p>
<p>If you have colonial ties, you may have an ancestor who fought for America’s freedom. Check out these collections to find out if your ancestor fought for America’s independence:</p>
<p>U.S. Revolutionary War Rolls, 1775-1783<br />
U.S. Compiled Revolutionary War Military Service Records, 1775-1783<br />
U.S. Revolutionary War Pensioners, 1801-1815, 1818-1872<br />
3. Convict</p>
<p>In the 18th century, the British government sent thousands of convicts to the American colonies to free up overcrowded prisons in England. Once America gained independence, convicts were sent to penal colonies in Australia.</p>
<p>British ships transported over 160,000 convicts to Australia between 1788 and 1868. Most of these convicts had been charged for petty crimes like theft or forgery.</p>
<p>Do you have a black sheep in your family? Take a look at convict transportation records and weekly newspapers (gazettes) published to report crimes and wanted criminal to find out more about your convict-ancestor:</p>
<p>UK, Police Gazettes, 1812-1902, 1921-1927<br />
Ireland, Police Gazettes, 1861-1893<br />
New South Wales and Tasmania, Australia Convict Musters, 1806-1849<br />
Australian Convict Transportation Registers – Other Fleets &amp; Ships, 1791-1868<br />
4. Sailor</p>
<p>What’s more exhilarating than traveling the world? When sailing ships dominated the Atlantic and Pacific, there were many reasons for a man to try a life at sea: profit, career-advancement, or simply adventure.</p>
<p>Prospective sailors could join the Navy (the arm of a nation’s military that operated at sea), or the Merchant Navy (mercantile fleets owned by governments or private shipping companies).</p>
<p>Explore these collections to maybe discover if one of your ancestors sailed the seas:</p>
<p>UK Royal Naval Seamen Index 1853-1872<br />
U.S. Deaths in US Naval Service, 1861-1867<br />
UK Apprentices Indentured in Merchant Navy, 1824-1910<br />
Indexes to Seamen’s Protection Certificate Applications and Proofs of Citizenship<br />
5. Royalty</p>
<p>If you have colonial ancestors, you might have British king and queens in your family tree. Over 600 colonists who settled in America have been confirmed as descendants of royalty.</p>
<p>Many high-status colonists were the younger sons of aristocratic families in England. By law they could not inherit land, so they struck out for America for better opportunities. Their aristocratic families often trace back to medieval royalty through female lines or children born out of wedlock.</p>
<p>Ancestry has databases for the 600 colonists with royal ties and for Burke’s Peerage, which catalogues families of nobility in England. Find out if you could descend from royalty:</p>
<p>The Royal Descents of 600 Immigrants<br />
Burke’s Family Records (Indexed)<br />
Burke’s Peerage and Baronetage Genealogical and Heraldic Dictionary</p>
<p>Your last name could also hold some clues that could help along your journey of royal roots discovery:</p>
<p>6. Inventor</p>
<p>Did your ancestor think outside the box? The 19th and 20thcenturies boomed with advancements in science, technology, and medicine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/12/22/nine-kinds-of-ancestors-you-could-find-on-your-family-tree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 60/63 objects using Redis
Page Caching using Redis 
Database Caching using Redis

Served from: _ @ 2023-12-30 11:50:47 by W3 Total Cache
-->